# WARENAS@GMAIL.COM W1ARENAS.GITHUB.IO

## WALTER L. ARENAS SOFTWARE ENGINEER STUART, FL

772-678-9451 LINKEDIN.COM/IN/WALTER-ARENAS

I am a dedicated and passionate full-stack software engineer that looks forward to implementing my 20-year experience in international sales and project management, plus my education in electrical engineering, into the development and maintenance of software. Such values include a strong work ethic, facing challenging goals, working under pressure, attention to detail, plus a problem-solving and result-oriented attitude. I possess the ability to adapt to new technologies and quickly learn them. Coupled with my mentoring nature, passion for public speaking, effective communication, collaboration, and teamwork, my unique skillset makes me a particularly valuable and well-rounded asset.

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

- Languages: Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Type Script
- Libraries and Frameworks: React, jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, Flexbox, Bootstrap
- Management & Deployment: Git, GitHub, command line
- Databases: PostgreSQL, Sequelize, ORM, Mongo DB, Mongoose, ODM
- Methodologies: Object Oriented Programming, Test-Driven Development, Responsive Design, Authentication, User Stories, ERDs, wireframing
- Other: RESTful Routing, JSON, Trello, APIs, FTP, CURL

#### TRANSFERABLE SKILLS

- While working in very diverse market sectors and worldwide cultures, I have developed the ability to express,
  with eloquence, intricate concepts in layman terms to diverse audiences. I can deliver with ease detailed
  instructions to end users and also provide efficient and concise executive summaries to corporate decision
  makers.
- Throughout my professional life, I have demonstrated successful leadership and management aptness in building teams thanks to my mentoring attitude, hands-on approach, acceptance of feedback, and fair recognition of efforts.
- My successful sales career has proven that I am able to gain—and am worthy of—the trust of teammates and clients thanks to my dependability and integrity.
- Expert computer skills (Word, PowerPoint, Salesforce, Outlook, Google suite, etc. Excel power user.)
- Peruvian native, fully fluent in Spanish. Some Portuguese and Italian.

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER IMMERSIVE STUDENT**

GENERAL ASSEMBLY, ATLANTA, GA

WWW.GENERALASSEMB.LY

Full time immersive student in Software Engineering. Nearly 500 hours of intense and challenging professional training over ten weeks. Utilized a hands-on approach to practice user-centered design methods, design thinking skills, team collaboration, and client relations. Developed a portfolio of in-class projects.

• Please, refer to my GitHub repository to view my projects,

#### SR. PROJECT MANAGER - IT

DMR CONSULTING (NOW PART OF FUJITSU AMERICA), ATLANTA, GA

WWW.FUJITSU.COM/US

JANUARY 2021 - PRESENT

- Consistently provided excellent results and met all project deliverables on time and on budget. Our history of success greatly contributed to the reputation of this young company, which led to its acquisition by Fujitsu America.
- Thanks to my ability to learn and adapt to new technologies, I became an asset to my company by providing services in the maintenance of legacy and client-server software to domestic and international clients in a variety of industries, including financial, banking, telecommunications, and manufacturing.

#### Relevant projects:

- Software development and maintenance: territory and commissions management Bell South (Atlanta, GA)
- Software assessment and conversion Extremo (Santiago, Chile), Banco Argentaria (Madrid, Spain), Telefónica de España (Madrid, Spain), South Shore Hospital (Bay Shore, NY).
- Contingency planning/business continuity: Powertel (Atlanta, GA), Chase Manhattan Bank (New York, NY).

#### WALTER L. ARENAS

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### INTERNATIONAL SALES DIRECTOR – LATIN AMERICA AND AFRICA SEPTEMBER 2014-JANUARY 2021

WATERBLASTING, L.L.C., STUART, FLORIDA

WWW.THEHOG.COM

American manufacturer of airport technology.

- Swiftly learned a new line of products and the intricacies of a new industry, which allowed prompt development of new markets. Sold \$875,000 in the first year to a region that had no sales in than five years.
- Surpassed the \$12M mark in sales in first three years.

#### INTERNATIONAL SALES MANAGER

NOVEMBER 2010-AUGUST 2014

AWARENESS TECHNOLOGY, INC., PALM CITY, FLORIDA

WWW.AWARETECH.COM

American manufacturer of *in-vitro* diagnostics (IVD) instrumentation and reagents.

- Rapidly promoted to International Sales Manager in charge of all ex-USA business as a direct report to the company's president thanks to an explosive success in sales of over 30% during my first year in a very challenging region.
- Established within my team a culture of up-selling and attentive and timely customer service, and relationship-based selling practices that produced steady double-digit growth year-over-year during my tenure.

#### INTERNATIONAL SALES MANAGER – LATIN AMERICA

2006-2010

UNITED PRODUCTS AND INSTRUMENTS, INC, SHANGHAI, CHINA

WWW.UNICOSCI.COM

- Restructured and developed a region that produced a modest \$350,000 per year to produce a dramatic 61% growth in sales during the first year and a subsequent and unprecedented 125% growth the second year.
- Established an in-house certification process to train technical support staff, which allowed distributors to gain the trust of end users and turned the region into a multi-million-dollar market

#### **EDUCATION**

| GENERAL ASSEMBLY / ADOBE DIGITAL ACADEMY              | Atlanta, GA        |
|---|--------------------|
| Software Engineering Immersive                        |                    |
| RUTGERS UNIVERSITY                                    | Piscataway, NJ     |
| Electrical Engineering                                |                    |
| BRIGHAM YOUNG UNIVERSITY - IDAHO                      | Rexburg, ID        |
| Engineering, Physics and Mathematics                  |                    |
| DMR CONSULTING GROUP (now part of Fujitsu Consulting) | Jersey City, NJ    |
| Trained in Project Management Institute standards     |                    |
| Lotus Notes, Administrator Certification              |                    |
| Microsoft Windows Certified Professional, NT          |                    |
| NOVELL CNE ADMINISTRATION - Certified Novell Engineer | Salt Lake City, UT |